there are tons and tons and tons of
kettle bells on the market but ironbull
is really starting to catch my eye with
their line of kettle bells these are
super affordable but how does the
quality Stack Up compared to the rest of
the competition stick around and we're
going to find
[Music]
out what's up everybody it's Jake back
in the barbing garage gym and for
today's video I'm going to take some
time talking about the iron bull kettle
bells if you're new to this whole
process in this video today I'm going to
tell you everything there is to know
about these kettle bells from the price
to some pros and cons and then of course
who should or maybe should not add these
to their home gym but before I do all
that just want to make sure youall know
that we have in fact reviewed a lot of
other kettle bells on barb. comom and we
do in fact have a best list of all of
our top choices so if you want check
that out all you got to do is search
barbend best kettle bells it's going to
pull right up for you you can find out
for yourself where this one lands on
that
[Music]
list okay so first of all I want to talk
about how beautiful of a kettle bell
this is it just looks great it's pretty
much aside from you know some dings that
happen during Transit this is a
beautiful Kettle bow it looks almost
perfect I really like the shine of this
powder coat finish that doesn't always
happen and with some other companies
it's more of a matte finish it's kind of
dull I really like how this is just kind
of bright and shiny especially with the
actual color coding right here you know
all companies have with their cast iron
kettle bells a colorcoded handle I
really like how bright this purple is
right here something about it it's just
aesthetically pleasing right now also
really like how the iron bull logo in
the front it's a little bit it sticks
out a little bit but not as bad as some
other companies and that's definitely
something that you want you don't want
to have an uncomfortable you know
experience with your kettle bell as it's
in the racked position on your arm it's
just not fun and that's definitely
something I don't think you have to
worry about right here this is a gravity
cast kobell meaning they pour the cast
iron into a mold gravity takes over from
there and that's what is leading to
evenly balanced weight with the kettle
bell it's definitely something that you
want you don't want it to be uneven or
anything like that but that also means
this is one single piece of cast iron
there's no welding right here a lot of
times on some lesser quality kettle
bells you can put your hands on the
handle and where that Bell meets and you
can feel like a seam and that's where
they've welded the two together if
you're somebody who only does kettle
bell workouts you're constantly doing
kettle bell swings and things of that
nature that is something to worry about
because that could come loose over time
now it's probably going to be years down
the road maybe you know I I can't tell
you exactly but it's something you don't
have to worry about here it's definitely
a good thing these are also extremely
affordable extremely affordable I'm
going to dig into it in a minute but
these are some of the most affordable I
don't want to say cheapest because it's
not that you know kind of a negative
connotation with that these are not
cheap by any means but as as you know as
far as affordability goes this is one of
the best options that's on the market
now only a one thing here in my opinion
that might make you not want to go and
purchase these and that's just the
weight range these are 9 to 70 lbs you
know some people want heavier than that
like I said especially if you're
somebody who only does kettle bell
workouts and you start to get really
strong and you want to push yourself
you're not going to be able to go past
70 lbs with these right
here all right let's dig into some money
now and first and foremost I got to
mention prices are always subject to
change I mean the amount of times where
I tell y'all something is x amount of
dollars the next thing I know it's
cheaper more expensive is ridiculous so
definitely keep that in mind price is
always subject to change but as of right
now these are probably the most
affordable highquality kettle bells that
you can find on the market all right so
this 44lb BT right here that cost you
about 80 bucks shipping is only about
$10 or so so you're basically spending
90 maybe closer to 100 bucks just on
this kettle bell that's a steal all
right so with kettle bell Kings their
44lb Bell right now is about 150 Deus
it's about like 170 and with Rogue you
know always got to talk about Rogue
Rogues are going to be about 110 or so
after shipping so this is like I said
one of the most affordable options
available these range from 9 to 70 lb so
you're looking at anywhere from 30 bucks
to 125 bucks whatever into the spectrum
that is these are some of the most
affordable options available so if
you're Balling on a budget maybe you're
wanting to make the most out of your
purchase and find you know the most high
quality and affordable kettle bells
available iron bus probably got you
covered all right so once again this is
a 44lb kettle bell but as I like to do
do we're going to weigh it really quick
and just see the
accuracy almost 46 lbs right there
45.7 that's totally fine totally
acceptable if it was you know 47 lb if
it was you 41 lb that's where you kind
of run into some trouble nothing wrong
with this at all nothing negative to say
about it now let's talk about this front
logo right here it's still recessed but
you know there's also some stuff that
sticks out it's totally fine you know
you get the kettle bell in that racked
position you can't really tell you know
sometimes with other companies where
that really sticks out like one comes to
mind is Nike Nike's came out with some
new Strength gear their logo it sticks
out so far that it really digs into my
skin and that just it's something I'm
not crazy about something you don't have
to worry about right here on the back
you've got your kilograms and pounds
this is all recessed nice and flat right
here this is going to be a nice
comfortable spot for you to you know
rest that up against your arm as I
mentioned earlier this is a beautiful
kettle bell it's pretty much polished
free of imperfections I do have you know
some dings in it right here but that's
that didn't happen you know during the
manufacturing process that happened from
A to B to get here to me so nothing
against iron Bull on that it's going to
happen with kettle bells trust me it's
happened so many times now the handle
right here is 38 mm it's not going to be
the same for all of them obviously you
know with cast iron kettle bells they go
up you know depending on the weight so
if you're looking for uniformity within
your kettle bells I'd definitely suggest
going after some competition ones
because their dimensions and everything
is all the same this also stands right
around 10 in tall or so so it's not the
same height I mean Dimensions across all
powder coat CLE Bells different
companies and everything they're all
different they all make them different
you know especially a lot of that has to
do with the base right here this is nice
and flat it's machine finished I can
just tell and there's you know no
imperfections or anything like that down
here so it's going to sit nice and flat
but there are some other companies that
have a wider base in general it takes up
you know more surface area so it's going
to probably wobble less but I have not
had any issues with this whatsoever
remember this is gravity cast there's no
welding right here whatsoever this is
about as structurally sound as you get
asked for it to be considering that low
price tag this is probably the best
budget kettle bell purchase you can make
I think these are an awesome option for
anybody who's balling on a budget but
also for anybody who wants to make the
most of their purchase by going after an
affordable product without SA
sacrificing quality these are really
high qualities that gravity cast the
powder coat feels really nice in my
hands these are going to last you a
really long time my opinion the only
reason not to purchase one of these
kettle bells is if you need more than 70
lbs of weight I honestly y'all I have
zero gripes against these that's about
it for
me all right well that's a wrap on
today's review over the iron bull kettle
bells because of the low price test my
big question going into this video was
regarding the quality and whether or not
these actually Stack Up compared to the
rest of the competition after spending a
lot of time with them I definitely think
that they do that gravity cast process
here is certainly felt I really like the
powder coat finish I just know that some
of y'all are going to wish that they had
more than 70 lbs of weight to offer
thanks for hanging out with me I hope
this video was really helpful and I was
able to tell you everything there is to
know about these kettle bells as always
keep your eyes peeled for my next video
but for now why don't you head over to
barb. comom because we have a full
written article about these kettle bells
I definitely think you should go and
check out all you got to do is search
barbend Iron bull kettle bell review
it's going to pull right up for you and
you can read over everything we
discussed here today now it's time for
me to get a workout in I'll catch youall
next
[Music]
[Applause]
time